Dr. Jonathan Belcher

Ph.D. Mathematics, CU Boulder

4650 White Rock Cir Apt 6
Boulder, CO 80301
☐ +1 (614) 390 8315
☑ jonathan.belcher@colorado.edu
❷ math.colorado.edu/~jobe9550

Professional Interests and Goals

I AM a passionate mathematician and educator with a background in non-commutative geometry, topology, functional analysis, and differential geometry. My goal is to apply my broad mathematical knowledge and teaching experience towards developing curricula in engineering and applied sciences. I also enjoy mentoring and motivating developing minds, helping to guide them towards career fields that will interest and inspire them. The current challenges our civilization faces are going to require a strong, disciplined, and insightful generation of people. With the setbacks of COVID-19 and diminishing efficacy of our K-12 educational programs, it is up to the innovation of our post-secondary institutions to make sure that the next generation has the preparation they need for our rapidly changing world. This is a challenge that excites and inspires me, and I love to work with institutions that feel similarly that education is one of the most powerful tools we have to change the world.

--- History

2022–Present **Post-Doctoral Teacher/Researcher**, Convex Optimization and Machine Learning, University of Colorado, Boulder

2019 – 2022 Mathematics Lecturer, University of Colorado, Boulder

2012 - 2019 Graduate Student in Mathematics, University of Colorado, Boulder

2009 - 2012 Education Editor, McGraw-Hill Education and Independent Contractor

2009 – 2009 Actuarial Contractor, Nationwide Insurance

Technical Skills

- Basics of Python, NumPy, SymPy, Jupyter Notebooks
- SQL scripting, Excel, and VBA, Nationwide Insurance
- C++ and Matlab intro courses, The Ohio State University
- YouTube Online Lecture Series, Teaching and Leadership

Education

May, 2019 Ph.D. Mathematics, University of Colorado, Boulder

May, 2016 M.A. Mathematics, University of Colorado, Boulder

June, 2009 B.S. Mathematics, The Ohio State University

June, 2009 B.S. Physics, The Ohio State University

Ph.D. Thesis

Title Bridge Cohomology: Generalizing Hochschild and Cyclic Cohomologies and applications to Chern-Weil Theory

 $Supervisor \quad {\bf Markus\ Pflaum}$

Publications

In preparation Bridge Cohomology: A generalization of Hochschild and cyclic cohomologies with applications to manifolds with boundary, Jon Belcher and Markus Pflaum

Mentoring

 $\begin{tabular}{lll} \it Thesis & {\bf A~Generalization~of~S-Divergence~to~Symmetric~Cone~Programming~via~Euclidean~Jor-Co-advising~dan~Algebra,~Zhuochen~(Jaden)~Wang \end{tabular}$

Math / Logan Martin - Geometric Unity, Mathematical Physics, Aerospace Engineering

Curriculum Kevin Stull - Natural Language Processing, Neurolink, Data Science, Machine Learning

Advising Dominic Glimp - Algebraic Topology, Differential Geometry, Analysis

Awards and Honors

 $\mathit{Talk}\$ Bridge Cohomology: Generalizing Hochschild and Cyclic Cohomologies via Triangulated Categories

Invited Online Global Noncommutative Geometry Seminar. Org: Xiang Tang, Guoliang Yu. Aug. 12, 2020

Invited AMS Special Session on Quantum Theory of Matter Meets Noncommutative Geometry and Topology, I. January 2020

Talk Bridge Cohomology: Generalizing Hochschild and Cyclic Cohomologies.

CIMPA School for Noncommutative Geometry. Meridas, Mexico. December 2018

AMS Fall Western Sectional. October 2018

K-Theory Conference, Argentina. July 2018

Texas A&M Noncommutative Geometry Conference. May 2018

FellowshipsAdele V. Leonhardy Memorial Scholarship, \$4K Summer 2018

> Summer 2017 University of Colorado Graduate School Summer Fellowship \$4.5K

Summer 2016 Sieglinde Haller Scholarship, \$4.5K

Certification Society of Actuaries Exam P

2008

Service

MathCommunity Contributions

The Geometry of Classical and Quantum Fields, Liber Mathematicae, Markus Pflaum, Jon Belcher (Contributing Author), www.libermath.org/GeometryClassicalAndQuantumFields/ Fall 2017

Gone Fishing: Conference on Poisson Geometry, Assistant Organizer, March 10-13, 2016 The Serre-Swan Theorem, expository paper contributed to The CRing Project, Akhil Mathew, M. Pflaum, et al., Spring 2016

Volunteering

Boulder Committee on Rights and Compensation - Board Member, Database and Membership Records Manager

Andy 24 Memorial Charity Event

2008 - 2010

2018-2019

Teaching Summary

MATH 2510: Intro to Statistics	5 Semesters
APPM 2360: Differential Equations with Linear Algebra	2 Semester
MATH 2130: Linear Algebra	1 Semester
APPM 2350: Calculus III for Engineers	2 Semesters
MATH 2400: Calculus III	2 Semesters
APPM 1360: Calculus II for Engineers	2 Semester
MATH 2300: Calculus II	3 Semesters
APPM 1350: Calculus I for Engineers	2 Semester
MATH 1300: Calculus I	3 Semester
MATH 1150: Precalculus	4 Semesters
MATH 1212: Data and Models	3 Semesters
MATH 1081: Business Calculus	1 Semester
MATH 1300: Calculus I	1 Semester
MATH 1150: Precalculus	2 Semesters
MATH 1011: College Algebra	1 Semester
	APPM 2360: Differential Equations with Linear Algebra MATH 2130: Linear Algebra APPM 2350: Calculus III for Engineers MATH 2400: Calculus III APPM 1360: Calculus II for Engineers MATH 2300: Calculus II APPM 1350: Calculus I for Engineers MATH 1300: Calculus I MATH 1150: Precalculus MATH 1212: Data and Models MATH 1081: Business Calculus MATH 1300: Calculus I MATH 1150: Precalculus MATH 1150: Precalculus

Inclusion

Diversity and Young Scholars Summer Bridge Program, The Ohio State University, Summer 2008

Work Experience

2009 - 2012 Education Editor, McGraw-Hill Education and Independent Contractor

• Edited online mathematical content using web applications

2009 – 2009 Actuarial Contractor, Nationwide Insurance

- Built and tested code factors for new life insurance products
- Fixed and reported on product defects through logical analysis of system code and databases with SQL and VBA